hey everybody welcome to this a1 english
listening practice video you can use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start remember to download the listening
time podcast and become a member at
patreon.com
listeningtime to receive my listening
practice seminars
okay today we're going to talk about
winter this isn't my favorite topic
because i prefer other seasons
but it's winter now so let's talk about
it in most places the weather is cold
during winter i don't live in a very
cold area but i still feel uncomfortable
during this season
i don't have a heating system in my
apartment this means that my apartment
isn't warm during winter so we have to
use extra blankets and wear warm clothes
inside and of course every time we go
outside we have to wear warm clothes too
in my city we often have cloudy weather
or sometimes rainy weather during this
season i don't like this but the worst
part of winter is that the days are
shorter the sun goes down really early
normally in the summer the sun sets
around 7 30 or 8 p.m in my city however
in december it sets before 5pm
many people don't like this because they
don't have many opportunities to enjoy
the sunlight when they finish working
it's already dark outside this can be
depressing i try to start working early
in the morning so i can finish early
this way i can have some hours of
sunlight after i'm done with work in
general i love the sun so i prefer long
summer days
not short winter days okay now let's
talk about some winter activities of
course some of the funnest winter
activities involve snow or ice for
example it's common to go skiing or
snowboarding during this time in the u.s
there are many ski resorts where people
can practice these sports if you don't
know how to ski or snowboard you can
also try sledding sledding is the
activity where you sit on something and
slide down a hill it's easy and fun
another fun thing you can do in the snow
is have a snowball fight this is where
you throw balls of snow at other people
everyone likes throwing snowballs at
people one other winter sport is ice
skating there are many places to ice
skate in the u.s even in the middle of
big cities i'm terrible at ice skating
but i still think it's fun
the only bad part is when you fall
because it hurts trust me okay now let's
talk about winter holidays and
traditions for me the best part of
winter is christmas i don't usually like
holidays but i love christmas my family
had several christmas traditions that
i'll always remember for example we
always decorated the christmas tree
together with the same ornaments every
year another tradition that i like is
going to see the beautiful lights and
decorations in different neighborhoods
i'm excited to start new christmas
traditions with my own family many
people around the world also celebrate
new year's eve in the u.s a lot of
people turn on the tv to watch the new
year's eve party in new york city i did
this when i was younger but nowadays
this holiday isn't really important to
me i like christmas but not new year's
eve
however when i'm with my wife's family i
have to celebrate this holiday with them
okay that's all for today
leave a comment and tell me your
favorite thing about winter before you
go remember to download the listening
time podcast and become a member at
patreon.com
listeningtime to receive my listening
practice seminars also subscribe to the
channel click on the bell and follow us
on instagram
i'll see you next time
[Music]